spoiler alert swimming popular form of
exercise easy on the joins turns out to
not be good for weight loss you're
working hard burning calories so why
don't the inches and pounds come off
watch the video to find out
[Music]
swimming and Aquatic exercise in general
are popular alternatives to land-based
activities such as walking or biking the
buoyancy helps take some of the
weight-bearing stress off the joints but
swimming appears to be less effective
for weight loss obese women were
randomized into an hour a day of walking
cycling or swimming six months later the
Walkers lost an average of 17 pounds the
cyclists lost an average of 19 pounds
and the swimmers didn't lose an ounce in
fact they actually gained five pounds
gauging skin folds that's made body fat
the measurement slimmed more than 40
percent of the walking and cycling
groups but there was no change at all in
the swimming group what's going on and
check this out the more the women walked
the more they lost weight the more the
women biked the more they lost weight
but the more lapse they did didn't seem
to matter even an hour a day no weight
loss what is going on
well it turns out that some exercise
boosts appetite more than others see
well land-based exercise does not
stimulate a compensatory increase in
appetite and calorie intake the same
cannot be said for water-based exercise
in contrast to walking
in contrast to running
and in contrast to cycling swimming can
significantly heighten hunger within
hours this may explain why swimmers tend
to have more body fat than Runners of
equal caliber even though they may be
actually expending more calories during
training if anything you'd think
swimming might lead to even greater
weight loss since you're losing heat to
the water but swimming didn't seem to
work at all
the cold it turns out may actually be
the culprit
if you exercise in warm water about 90
degrees Fahrenheit it does not boost
your appetite more than exercising on
land after the same workout in Cool
Water about 70 degrees Fahrenheit people
can end up eating more than twice as
much in a meal an hour later maybe
they're just burning off extra calories
to stay warm no even at the same number
of calories expended people eat hundreds
of calories more after exercising in
cold water offered a buffet after
burning off about 500 calories in Cool
Water people eat nearly 900 calories
hundreds more than after exercising warm
water or just staying dry so they ended
up taking in about twice as many
calories as they exercised off no wonder
swimming doesn't appear useful for
weight loss would the same thing happen
under different temperatures on land a
team of British researchers sought to
find out randomizing people to briskly
walk for 45 minutes on a treadmill in
the cold about 46 degrees Fahrenheit or
closer to room temperature but 68
degrees Fahrenheit participants were
then presented with a buffet meal in
which their eating was covertly recorded
and calorie intake was significantly
greater after exercising in the cold the
walking is often prescribed for
overweight individuals the researchers
conclude if walking was to take place in
a cold environment such as in the winter
then this may stimulate food intake in
the warmer months though obesity
researchers suggest exercising Outdoors
may be preferable to an air-conditioned
gym
all studies to date on the effects of
hot and cold environments I found that
exercising in cool water or under cool
conditions on land led to an increase in
post-workout calorie intake what about a
quick dip in the pool after you exercise
Australian researchers found that
immersion in water for 15 minutes cool
or warm after a running session resulted
in increased calorie intake what is it
about getting wet that what's your
appetite and maybe they gotta chill
after getting out before they could
change into dry clothes this suggests
that throw a cool shower after workout
may be invigorating it might be better
to stick to hot
[Music]